NYSUT President's Office Files. 6174/001
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Series Presidents files: Subseries 2
  - NYSUT Board Mailings, 1994 (Box 78, Folder 20)
    April 1994. Mail ballots; memo re health care reform legislative update; NYSUT Legislative Memorandums in support of various bills; Division of Research & Educational Services Monthly Report, April; recommendations re agency fee reduction procedures; guest editorial by NYSUT executive vice president Alan Lubin, "School Boards Are Passing the Buck on Tenure"; packet of newspaper clippings, "NYSUT in the News: Taking the Initiative: 1994 RA Media Coverage, with cover memo from Linda Rosenblatt; opinion piece in Schenectady Gazette, "Teaches miss more classes than students," and letter to the editor rebuttal by Tom Hobart; Education Week article on the Board of Regents, "A Throne of Contention," April 27, 1994; newsletter of American Federation of Teachers Communications Association members, AFTCAtalyst, April 1994; NYSUT Legislative Memorandums opposing bills; Executive Committee meeting minutes of March 3, 1994; Board of Directors' meeting minutes of March 3 and 6; letter to Committee of 100 members re lobbying day; press release, "NYSUT Leaders Named as Observers for South Africa Vote," April 11; report by AFL-CIO Committee on the Evolution of Work, "The New American Workplace: A Labor Perspective," February 1994; AFTCAtalyst, February-March 1994; NYSUT newsletter, For Your Health Safety, winter 1994; newsletter for NYSUT employees and retirees, published by the Public Relations Department, The Chalkboard, re retirements and other personnel changes, April 1994
  - NYSUT Board Mailings, 1994 (Box 78, Folder 21)
    May 1994 (folder 1 of 2). RAND document, "Potential Sources of Union Opposition to NASDC [New American Schools Development Corporation] Designs," with cover memo from Tom Hobart warning of threat if Republicans return to the federal government, May 6, 1994; NYSUT press release, "Pensions, Taylor Law Reform Targets of NYSUT Committee of 100," May 3; newspaper clippings re delegation of NYSUT and other officials to monitor South Africa elections; NYSUT Legislative Memorandums in support of various bills; newsletter for chapter leaders of United University Professions, The Connection, recounting poll-watching experience in South Africa, May 4, 1994; United University Professions newsletter, The Voice, April; newsletter, The Retiree Organizer, April; report on attendance at 1994 Representative Assembly; NYSUT Information Bulletin: The Privatization of Public Schools: Subcontracting Service: non-teaching, teaching, and management; Kappan Special Report on public education's encounter with the religious right, May 1994; Censorship Follow-up: Questionnaire for presidents of elementary and secondary teacher locals, 1993-94; Division of Research & Educational Services Monthly Report, May; AFT newsletter, On the Hill, featuring status of health care legislation, May
  - NYSUT Board Mailings, 1994 (Box 78, Folder 22)
    May 1994 (folder 2 of 2). Council of Chief State School Officers summary of the Goals 2000: Educate America Act; Council of School Superintendents press release, "Superintendents Say New Compact for Learning Produces Important Changes in State's Schools," May 3; article in History Matters newsletter from National Council for History Education, Inc., "The Social Studies and Curriculum Changes in New York State," noting changes posed great dangers for the teaching of history in that they allowed too much local flexibility and were devoid of content, vol. 6, no. 9, May; newsletter, The Summer Times (NYSUT-AFT Summer Learning Calendar 1994), with cover press release, "Great Summer Projects for Kids in Free Calendar from Teachers," May 13; NYSUT Legislative Memorandums supporting or opposing various bills; memo re Regents' policy paper on least restrictive environment, May 26; NYSUT press release, "Visiting Nurses Set to Strike for Fair, Equitable Contract," May 25; report of the NEA Special Committee on Relationships with Other Organizations, April 1; United University Professions newsletter, The Voice, May; NYSUT Regents' Report Card, May; newsletter, The Retiree Organizer, May
  - NYSUT Board Mailing, 1994 (Box 78, Folder 23)
    June 9, 1994. Mail ballot to replace Mark Chaykin with Ed Corcoran as regional staff director of Elmsford Regional Office; reports, 1994-95 State Aid Projections and State Aid to Education Package, with cover memo from Alan Lubin; AFT report, The Private Management of Public Schools: An Analysis of the EAI Experience in Baltimore; NYSUT Information Bulletin: The Privatization of Public Schools Subcontracting Service: non-teaching, teaching and management; Division of Research & Educational Services Monthly Report, June; newsletter, The Retiree Organizer, June; NYS AFL-CIO Unity newsletter, April; letter to Newsday in response to editorial calling for teacher salary caps, June 7; NYSUT Legislative Memorandums supporting or opposing various bills; NYSUT newsletter, For Your Health Safety, spring
  - NYSUT Board Mailings, 1994 (Box 78, Folder 24)
    June 17, 1994. Tentative agenda of Board of Directors meeting of June 28; NYSUT Budget 1994-95; Executive Committee minutes of February 11, March 3, April 14, May 7, and June 9, 1994; proposed assignment of resolutions referred to Board of Directors; memo on reauthorization of IDEA (Individuals with Disabilities Education Act), June 16; invitation to breakfast meeting for NYS delegates to AFT convention; NYSUT Legislative Memorandums supporting or opposing various bills; newsletter of American Federation of Teachers Communications Association members, AFTCAtalyst, May-June
  - NYSUT Board Mailings, 1994 (Box 78, Folder 25)
    July 1994. Memo re Waterford-Halfmoon opinion on payment of increments, July 8; summary of actions of June 28, 1994, Board of Directors meeting; NYSUT Legislative Memorandums supporting various bills; NYS AFL-CIO Unity newsletter, May, June; draft memo from State Education Department attorney, summarizing commissioner's decisions on attendance policies, with cover memo from NYSUT vice president Antonia Cortese, July 15; NYSUT Information Bulletin re Goals 2000: Educate America Act; NYSUT press release, "Teachers to Work with Solidarity [Polish labor union] on English, Classroom Techniques," July 12; announcement of Teacher Center grant awards
  - NYSUT Board Mailings, 1994 (Box 78, Folder 26)
    August 1994. List of endorsements for governor, lieutenant governor, comptroller, attorney general, U.S. Senate, House of Representatives, NYS Senate, and NYS Assembly; NYSUT press release, "NYSUT Endorses Cuomo for Re-Election," August 10; Report on the 1994 NEA Representative Assembly; agenda for Board of Directors meeting of August 10; updated NYSUT telephone directory; Statement of Thomas R. Donahue, Secretary-Treasurer, AFL-CIO on the Fact-Finding Report of the Commission on the Future of Worker-Management Relations, with cover memo from AFL-CIO president Lane Kirkland re report of the Dunlop Commission, June 1; NYS AFL-CIO announcement of Harry VanArsdale, Jr., Memorial Community Services Award to Karen Duffy, United University Professions, Geneseo chapter, with cover memo from Tom Hobart, August 5; NYSUT Regents' Report Card, July; newsletter for NYSUT employees and retirees, published by the Public Relations Department, The Chalkboard, July; memo from Antonia Cortese, updating on variances; NYSUT press releases, "NYSUT Endorses Moynihan, Congressional Candidates," August 18, and "NYSUT-SED Team Up to Improve Services to the Disabled," August 22; NYSUT Information Bulletin re classroom teacher salaries, 1993-94; agreement, Alliance between the New York State United Teachers and the State Education Department's Office of Vocational and Educational Services for Individuals with Disabilities to Achieve Increased Collaboration for Teachers and Other Members with Disabilities; NYS AFL-CIO Unity newsletter, special convention issue announcing endorsement of Mario Cuomo, August 1994
  - NYSUT Board Mailings, 1994 (Box 78, Folder 27)
    September 1994. Major Policy Statements of the Board of Regents of the University of the State of New York: 1968-1993; 1994 Annual Report of the New York State Senate Standing Committee on Education; NYS AFL-CIO Unity newsletter, September; NYSUT Regents' Report Card; NYSUT press release, "Union-Busting Try Unites Area Teachers behind Greenburgh 11," September 27; Testimony of Antonia Cortese, First Vice President, NYSUT, to the Board of Regents and New York State Education Department at Their 1995 Legislative Conference, September 21, 1994; Division of Research & Educational Services Monthly Report, September; NYSUT press release, "NYSUT Backs Burstein for Attorney General," September 29; memo to Retiree Council leaders re rationale for announcing endorsements for Senate and Assembly, September 30; NYSUT Information Bulletin re Alternatives to Special Education, revised September 1994; memo re financial controls for dues, September 12; United University Professions newsletter, The Voice, September; newsletter for chapter leaders of United University Professions, The Connection; updates on variances
  - NYSUT Board Mailings, 1994 (Box 78, Folder 28)
    October 1994. Minutes of Board of Directors meetings of June 28 and August 19; tentative agenda for meeting of October 14; Executive Committee meeting minutes of August 10; letter to local president re designating representative to Committee of 100; "Talking Points Pro-Cuomo - Then and Now" (includes bullet points against Pataki and for Karen Burstein and Carl McCall); NYSUT press releases, "NYSUT Endorses Candidates for Senate, Assembly," October 5, and "Property Taxes Would Skyrocket under Pataki Tax Plan," October 4; list of individual endorsements; NYSUT Retiree Handbook; Summary of Actions of Board of Directors meeting of October 14-15; letter from NYSUT executive vice president Alan Lubin on behalf of VOTE/COPE political action committee, warning of financial disaster to school districts if Pataki budget cuts go in effect, with attached scenarios by district; NYSUT press release, "Pataki Tax Plan 'All Trick and No Treat,' Analysis Shows," October 31; memo re address changes for new board members; newsletter of American Federation of Teachers Communications Association members, AFTCAtalyst, September-October
  - NYSUT Board Mailings, 1994 (Box 78, Folder 29)
    November 1994. Tentative agenda for Board of Directors meeting of December 2-3, 1994; NYSUT Information Bulletin re NYS Mentor Teacher Internship Program; memo sent to local presidents and attached list of election results across New York State, noting losses in governor's and attorney general's race; recommendations of Committee on Referred Resolutions; Representative Assembly Action Items and Information Items; memo re AFT criteria for judging high quality standards, November 17; action item for the Board of Regents, "Recommendations for Refinement of the Organization of the Office of Elementary, Middle, Secondary and Continuing Education (EMSC)," with cover memo from Antonia Cortese re mid-course correction at State Education Department; local presidents' survey, 1994-95; memo re reappointment of members of the Board of Regents; NYSUT press release, "NYSUT Urges Time Off for Parent-Teacher Conferences, Says Parental Involvement Key to Academic Success," November 14; Tips for the Parent-Teacher Conference (aimed at parents); NYSUT Information Bulletin, "Prisoners of Time: Report of the National Education Commission on Time and Learning"; "Status Report on Voluntary National Standards in Education," second edition, October 1994; newsletters: The Chalk Board, The Retiree Organizer, The Voice (United University Professions); memo from Hobart re NEA-AFT merger talks, November 21
  - NYSUT Board Mailings, 1994 (Box 78, Folder 30)
    December 1994. Summary of actions of Board of Directors meeting of December 2-3, 1994; memos re PERB Decisions in Waterford-Halfmoon case, December 5 and 7; AFT memo re AFT-NEA merger discussions, December 2; State Education Department memo re application process for funding of local partnerships under the federal School-to-Work Opportunities Act, December 2; NYS AFL-CIO memo re boycott of Wal-Mart, K-Mart, and other discount retailers, with attached instructions on where to look for the union label on garments; NYSUT press release, "Parents Should Combine Holiday Fun with Learning: Stress Reading, Writing and Educational Toys, NYSUT Says," December 12; newsletter, The Retiree Organizer; The 1995 Educator's Income Tax Guide; NYSUT Information Bulletin, "New York State Goals 2000 Grants," December 1994
  - NYSUT Board Mailings, 1995 (Box 79, Folder 1)
    January 1995. NYSUT press release, "Reaction to Gov. George Pataki's State of the State Address," January 4, 1995; text of the address: Message to the Legislature, Governor George Pataki, January 4, 1995; newspaper clipping from Albany Times Union re State of the State address; cover memo re attached op-ed piece by Tom Hobart, "School Boards Are Passing the Buck on Tenure," in response to editorial, with Hobart article as printed in Rochester Democrat and Chronicle, "The Tenure Trap"; Regents' Report Card (NYSUT report on recent actions of the Board of Regents), December 1994; NYS AFL-CIO Unity newsletter, November-December 1994; Board of Directors photo directory and Election District map of NYS, 1995; questionnaire for presidents of locals representing school-related personnel in public schools, 1994-95; letter to Tom Hobart from United Farm Workers re victorious Bear Creek Productions representation election, January 3; article from Inside AFT, "AFT and NEA Agree to End Merger Talks," January 9; NYSUT press release, "NYSUT Backs Bills to Outlaw Cybersex with Minors," January 12; Division of Research & Educational Services Monthly Report, January 1995; NYSUT Information Bulletin re Application for Twenty-First Century Schools; legislative update memo, January 20; letter to Committee of 100 members re lobbying day, January 19; report, Implementation of Actions by the 1994 Representative Assembly; New York Times clipping, "Even the Wealthiest Suburbs Are Beginning to Revolt Against School Spending," January 18; tentative agenda for Board of Directors meeting of February 3-4; update on variances; AFT Goals 2000 Update, vol. 1, no. 1, January; NYSUT Information Bulletin, "Teacher Salaries, Experience, Preparation, and Turnover, 1988-89 to 1993-94"; NYSUT Legislative Memorandum in support of supplemental pension bill; NYSUT newsletter, The Retiree Organizer, January; NYS AFL-CIO Unity newsletter, January
  - NYSUT Board Mailings, 1995 (Box 79, Folder 2)
    February 1995. Summary of actions of Board of Directors meeting of February 3; memo from acting deputy Commissioner of Education re length of school day and other regulations, January; NYSUT Regent's Report Card; memo re agency fee refund; NYSUT Briefing Bulletins, "Should the Board of Regents Be Abolished?" "The State's $5 Billion Deficit for 1995-96," "Gearing Up for School Voucher Initiatives," "Are 21st Century Schools Another Promise?" and "Status of Curriculum Frameworks and Revised Assessments"; NYSUT Legislative Memorandum in support of building aid for Floyd School District; AFL-CIO Unity newsletter, January; United University Professions newsletter, The Voice, February
  - NYSUT Board Mailings, 1995 (Box 79, Folder 3)
    March 1995. 1995 Representative Assembly Local Presidents' Conference briefing book, Current Legal Issues, prepared by NYSUT Office of General Counsel; NYSUT Information Bulletins, "The Privatization of Public Schools Subcontracting Service: non-teaching, teaching and management" and "Report on the NYSUT Survey of Presidents of Elementary and Secondary Teacher Locals, 1994-95" (re censorship, student cheating, new teachers, nursing tasks assigned to teachers, special education, shared decision-making, organized anti-tax groups); NYSUT press release, "NYSUT Convention a $3.7 Million Boost to Rochester Economy," February 27; New York Times clipping re merger of ILGWU and ACTWU, February 20; NYSUT newsletter, The Retiree Organizer, February; AFT newsletter, On the Hill, "GOP Takes Over," February; tentative agenda for Board of Directors meeting of March 16; minutes of February 3 meeting; memo to Executive Committee from vice president Antonia Cortese re Special Order of Business on Regents Examinations and State Standards, March 7; 1995 Representative Assembly Special Order of Business Regarding the Governor's Proposals in the Area of Special Education; Regarding Instruction in the Middle Grades; Mandate Relief and Regents' Authority; National Board for Professional Teaching Standards; Opposition to the Governor's Proposal Regarding Higher Education Funding; Master Planning for Higher Education; United University Professions newsletter, The Voice, March; NYSUT press releases, "NYSUT to Raise Curtain on Annual Convention; Tougher Discipline, Higher Academic Standards Top Agenda," March 7, "NYSUT Committee of 100 to Press Case for More School Aid," March 2, "Sobol, NYSUT Delegates Blast Pataki's Budget," March 18, "NYSUT Launches Ad Blitz Against Governor's Education Cuts," March 20; NYSUT Information Bulletin, "School Budget Votes and Contingency Budgets"; 1995 Representative Assembly Report on Attendance; Report of the AFT Delegation to Japan; NYSUT Briefing Bulletin, "NYSUT's Program for a Comprehensive Safe Schools Act," "Accountability and Title I," "National Hospital and Medical School Salaries," "Executive Budget Proposals Would End Special Education Standards in New York State"; "Student Cheating" (results of questionnaire of local presidents re incidence); "NYSUT Policy on Raising Student Achievement and High Academic Standards," "Censorship Incidents on the Rise"; newsletter, AFT Privatization Alert, spring 1995; NYSUT Regents' Report Card; NYSUT Legislative Memorandums supporting or opposing various bills
  - NYSUT Board Mailings, 1995 (Box 79, Folder 4)
    April 1995. Testimony of Thomas Y. Hobart, president, NYSUT, to the Legislative Commission on Skills Development and Vocational Education on School-to-Work Transition in New York State, April 4, 1995; letter to Committee of 100 members re lobbying day; Representative Assembly attendance report; NYSUT Briefing Bulletins, "New York State Insurance Program Domestic Partner Coverage," "Cuts in Federal School Lunch Program Harm New York State Students," "Providing for Students' Special Health Care Needs"; NYSUT Information Bulletin, "1994-95 Goals 2000 Grant Awards," "Teacher Salaries and Inflation - 1973-74 to 1993-94," other topics; NYSUT Division of Research and Educational Services Monthly Report, April; NYSUT newsletters, The Retiree Organizer, March and April; NYSUT Legislative Memorandums supporting or opposing various bills; summary of actions of Board of Directors meeting of March 16; NYS AFL-CIO Unity newsletter, "Labor Battles Executive Budget," March-April; memo from vice president Antonia Cortese re provision of nursing and health-related services in schools, April 17, with attached document from State Education Department; memo re 1995-96 agency fee advance reduction, April 20; memo re NYSUT Task Force on Elementary School Standards, April 20; press release from NYS Labor-Religion Coalition, "Labor, Religion Unite to Fight Proposals That Hurt People," April 17; United University Professions newsletter, The Voice, April; NYSUT press releases, "Three NYSUT Leaders Named as Delegates to White House Conference," April 14, "Teachers Union Sues Children's Village in First Amendment Case," April 28; letters from Oklahoma State AFL-CIO re Oklahoma City bombing; NYSUT newsletter, The Chalkboard, April
  - NYSUT Board Mailings, 1995 (Box 79, Folder 5)
    May 1995. NYSUT Legislative Memorandums supporting various bills; newsletter of American Federation of Teachers Communications Association members, AFTCAtalyst, April; NYSUT Briefing Bulletins; NYSUT Information Bulletin, "Compensation in the Private Sector"; NYSUT Regents' Report Card; 1995-96 dues schedule; 1995 QuEST Conference materials; press release from State Education Department announcing School-to-Work Advisory Council Local Partnership Awards, May 15; summary of 1995 Representative Assembly delegate evaluations, May 18; AFT memo re NEA Board of Directors' action on proposed merger, May 11; NYSUT Legislative Memorandums in support of various bills; mail ballot for selection of members to Task Force on Elementary School Standards, May 12; confidential report for NYSUT elected leaders and staff re nineteenth annual NEA-NY Delegate Assembly, April 28-30, 1995; memo, registration form, and related information re New Local Presidents' Conference, May 12; NYSUT press release, "25 Percent of Teachers in NYSUT Survey Report Guns in Schools," May 15; United University Professions newsletter, The Voice, May; letter to AFT leaders from president Al Shanker, decrying internal conflict within AFL-CIO, urging support for president Lane Kirkland, May 10; NYSUT Division of Research and Educational Services Monthly Report, May; NYSUT newsletter, The Retiree Organizer, May; newsletter for chapter leaders of United University Professions, The Connection, May 3
  - NYSUT Board Mailings, 1995 (Box 79, Folder 6)
    June 9, 1995. 1995-96 State Aid Projections (preliminary estimate payable under section 3609 plus other aids), with summary of Education Budget Bill and cover memo from NYSUT executive vice president Alan Lubin; NYSUT press releases, "Rally Planned for Fired Unionist Seeking Justice," re firing of teachers' aids at Children's Village, June 9, and "NYSUT Urges Codes of Conduct to Curb Rise in Student Cheating," June 12; ad deadlines and production schedule for New York Teacher and Bottom Line; NYSUT Briefing Bulletin; NYSUT Information Bulletins; NYSUT Legislative Memorandums supporting various bills; agenda for NYS AFL-CIO 1995 Biennial Community Services Conference; NYSUT telephone directory
  - NYSUT Board Mailings, 1995 (Box 79, Folder 7)
    June 16, 1995. NYSUT 1995-96 budget; tentative agenda for Board of Directors meeting of June 26-27, 1995; minutes of Board of Directors and Executive Committee meetings of March 16; minutes of Executive Committee meetings of April 6 and May 11; memo from Tom Hobart recommending list of members of committee to consider biannual instead of annual conventions, with attached resolution referred by Representative Assembly, June 16; memo re proposed revision of mailing label policy
  - NYSUT Board Mailings, 1995 (Box 79, Folder 8)
    July 1995. Summary of actions of Board of Directors meeting of June 26-27; newsletter of American Federation of Teachers Communications Association members, AFTCAtalyst, May/June; NYSUT pocket calendar; NYSUT in the News clippings, with cover memo; NYSUT Legislative Memorandum in support a new facility for CUNY Graduate Center; NYSUT Information Bulletins, "Building a School-to-Work System in New York" and "SED Guidelines: Teacher Aides & Teaching Assistants; NYSUT local leaders guide to handling the news media, "Making the News, Framing the Message"; NYSUT guide to programs, services, and publications, revised July 1995; memo re early retirement incentive law; NYSUT Briefing Bulletins; NYS AFL-CIO Unity newsletter, "A Future for Manufacturing in New York State," June; AFT newsletter, On the Hill, "Republican Budgets Pass Both House and Senate," re trillion-dollar federal budget cut, June
  - NYSUT Board Mailings, 1995 (Box 79, Folder 9)